‫All right.
‫So before we jump in and we start writing our HTML and CSS for this project, I just want to talk a
‫little bit about design and ideas.
‫So it really depends.
‫Sometimes you'll get a job as a front end developer and you'll have a designer on your team that will
‫create the UI and create the designs and then hand them off to you.
‫So usually it'll be like maybe a Photoshop file or a sketch file illustrator or some kind of graphic
‫design program.
‫And then it's your job to take that design and use HTML and CSS and possibly some JavaScript to recreate
‫that.
‫So, so that it actually runs in the browser as a website or a web app.
‫Now, a lot of the times you don't have the luxury of having a designer.
‫You'll have to actually create everything, come up with the ideas on your own, especially if you're
‫doing freelancing where you do absolutely everything.
‫So what I usually do is I look at other websites and other themes for inspiration, and a good way to
‫do that is to search like theme sites.
‫So, for instance, Bootstrap has a lot of really nice themes.
‫Bootstrap is actually a framework in each HTML, CSS framework.
‫I have an entire course in bootstrap if you want to learn more about it.
‫But let's say we search for bootstrap themes and there's going to be all types of sites that have different
‫themes.
‫Let's just go to this one here.
‫Themes dot get bootstrap and we can go down here and you can see some examples.
‫Some of them are websites and some are like admin interfaces like this.
‫That's not really what we're interested right now.
‫But let's take this site, for example, and this is actually selling for $50.
‫And that's another idea for you guys.
‫If you get good at this after this course and you can create some decent layouts, you can actually
‫sell them online.
‫But most of these sites have a live preview.
‫So let's take a look at that.
‫So what I would do is I would take a look at this layout and I would just get some ideas.
‫So look at the header, look at how things are laid out, how the logo looks, the background image.
‫Okay.
‫So that's that's really the, the what's popular right now is to have the main large image with just
‫a little bit of text and maybe some buttons.
‫And then underneath that, have some boxes and you'll see that over and over.
‫And that's really what's in right now.
‫It's to keep it very clean, you know, not not crazy colours, just maybe, you know, two, two or
‫maybe three colours with some light greys and and some dark colours.
‫But it's pretty simple.
‫And down here we have some demo pages like the services page, which again we just have a large background
‫with some, with some text over it.
‫If we go down we have three boxes with some icons.
‫So icons are really big down here.
‫You can see just have some text, some images laid out.
‫There's some animation in this theme, but of course you don't need to add the animation.
‫I'm actually not a fan of a lot of animation and again, just icons in text, just like we have right
‫here.
‫So you'll see this over and over.
‫So just go to different theme sites and get some ideas, get some inspiration and don't copy them.
‫I'm not saying just, you know, take exactly what they did and redo it, but take in some of the ideas
‫from maybe four or five different themes and create something of your own.
‫So that's what I do.
‫That's how I create my websites and user interfaces.
‫I'm far from a graphic designer, but I think I have at least some some eye for design.
‫And it's not that hard.
‫Just take some some examples for inspiration.
‫All right.
‫So that's it.
‫I just wanted to kind of talk a little bit about that before we get started.
‫So in the next video, we're going to start to write our HTML.